<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-09-26T06:59:33+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">RadicalXChange France</title><subtitle></subtitle><author><name>Olivier Milla</name><email>olivier.milla@hey.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Introduction to the 4th roundtable at Unesco Global Conference on Internet for Trust</title><link href="/2023/02/23/Introduction-to-the-4th-roundtable-at-Unesco-Global-Conference-on-Internet-for-Trust/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction to the 4th roundtable at Unesco Global Conference on Internet for Trust" /><published>2023-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2023/02/23/%20Introduction%20to%20the%204th%20roundtable%20at%20Unesco%20Global%20Conference%20on%20Internet%20for%20Trust</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/02/23/Introduction-to-the-4th-roundtable-at-Unesco-Global-Conference-on-Internet-for-Trust/"><![CDATA[<p><em>The following introduction was given by RadicalXChange France as the opening of the 4th roundtable of the <a href="https://www.unesco.org/en/internet-conference">UNESCO Global Conference on Internet for Trust</a> that was held in Paris, France on February 21 2023.</em></p>

<p><em>The even was co-organized by RadicalXChange France, <a href="https://leplusimportant.org/">#leplusimportant</a> and the <a href="https://www.tesaco.fr/">#TESaCo programme</a>.</em></p>

<hr />

<p>The first UNESCO initiative with regards to information as a public good was the Windhoek declaration back in 1991. 7 years later, 2 graduates from Stanford founded Google. Another 5 years later, a student out of Harvard founded Facebook. Obviously since then, digital information went into rapid mutation.</p>

<p>This last roundtable of the day has a specific mindset: we want to make the UNESCO guidance work and last anywhere on Earth.</p>

<p>I’m Christophe Gauthier of Radical Xchange, we are a global community committed to inspire radical social change. Together with my colleague, Malik, who is connected out of Buenos Aires, we will be co-moderating this roundtable.</p>

<p>We’re pleased to welcome the presence of <a href="https://twitter.com/JessicaFjeld">Jessica Fjeld</a> from Harvard and <a href="https://twitter.com/persily">Nate Persily</a> from Stanford, the very same universities which nurtured Google and Facebook and countless others. Jess and Nate will both help us understand what is at stake with digital platforms with online activity and human rights or with regulation and democracy. They will help us understand what’s coming next and how to tackle it.</p>

<p>Dear Audience, they will tell us that we need to act swiftly because “the future is happening much sooner than we had expected”.
Actually, this is a quote from our third panelist Stephanie Borg from DiploFoundation in Switzerland. Stephanie will be taking us through the new content generation and new disinformation capabilities, as well as all these different risks that have recently appearing over the horizon and rapidly gaining speed.</p>

<p>What should we all do then? In the last few weeks, the RadicalXchange team ran a speculative design experiment with the talented speakers that you’ve been listening to, all day. its aim was to strengthen the UNESCO guidance with operational suggestions. Here are 3 of the take aways:
Classify platform data. we call for a leverage of existing taxonomy and standardization processes, especially processes that passed the proof of time
Establish multi-scale and multi-stakeholder social media councils. We believe they should be granted them special platform rights, within a defined regulatory sandbox. Tailor various types of access, depending on their credentials.
Steer virality towards reliable information, that includes some experts teaching human rights to algorithms and human rights different variations depending on each geography and culture</p>

<p>Please stay online 5’ at the end of this roundtable to have your go at it.</p>

<p>These take-aways take us first to a major call for some regulation upgrade. For once , it seems to form a peculiar consensus that pushes all players at the same time from governments to regulatory bodies, from the Civil Society to the private sector. Some fear a direct threat to political stability. Others fear some competition bias.</p>

<p>This global momentum comes with its bucket of surprises. One of the first ruling with regard to generative AI comes surprisingly out of China. The same China  that adopted some privacy regulations, very similar to GDPR in Europe. This helps me introduce our fourth panelist, Asha Allen of the Center for Democracy and Technology in Brussels. She deals about the potential challenges of accessing digital platform data and the usefulness of this access.</p>

<p>Second, the UNESCO framework talks about co-regulation, it means we want to avoid at the same time misuse and abuse, but we also want to unveil censorship, dressed under the flattering outfit of regulators. Sergueï Gouriev is a professor at the Paris Science Po and a dissident from Russia. He calls them “spin dictators”.  With regards to finding the right balance, the framework suggests a multi-stakeholder approach. This is precisely what our fifth guest will be talking about. Let me welcome Bob Fay from Canada, he is Managing Director at Center of International Governance Innovation in Canada.</p>

<p>And finally this multi-stakeholder approach needs to address some differences depending on regions and communities. Malavika Jayaram from the Digital Asia hub will able to join us because of flight problems. as other speakers told today, she stresses on the importance of involving local communities, especially in the case where some local norms and cultures could conflict with Global standards.</p>]]></content><author><name>Olivier Milla</name><email>olivier.milla@hey.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The following introduction was given by RadicalXChange France as the opening of the 4th roundtable of the UNESCO Global Conference on Internet for Trust that was held in Paris, France on February 21 2023.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Unesco Global conference on internet for Trust - Paris Feb 21-23</title><link href="/2023/01/16/Unesco-Global-Conference-on-Internet-for-Democracy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Unesco Global conference on internet for Trust - Paris Feb 21-23" /><published>2023-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2023/01/16/Unesco%20Global%20Conference%20on%20Internet%20for%20Democracy</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/01/16/Unesco-Global-Conference-on-Internet-for-Democracy/"><![CDATA[<p>On February 21-23, 2023, UNESCO will hold a 3-day conference on the topic of Internet for Trust in its Parisian headquarters. The <a href="https://www.unesco.org/en/internet-conference">event</a> is co-organized by <a href="https://www.radicalxchange.org/">#RadicalXChange</a> France, <a href="https://leplusimportant.org/">#leplusimportant</a> and the <a href="https://www.tesaco.fr/">#TESaCo programme</a>.</p>

<p>RadicalXChange France will conduct <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speculative_design">#speculative design</a> interviews of participants in relationship with three topics:</p>
<ul>
  <li>How to organize the access to platform data for regulatory claims or open research purposes?</li>
  <li>How could digital platform governance interact with users in a manageable way?</li>
  <li>What kind of safeguards will be needed to filter facts and fakes 10 years from now?</li>
</ul>

<p>These topics challenge our interviewees about new issues to come 10 years from now or about new emerging stakeholders.</p>

<p>The summary of the collected interviews will be shared as an introduction to the last roundtable of the day : <em>UNESCO guidance for regulating digital platforms: how to secure effective implementation?</em></p>

<p>The interview material will also be shared publicly here.</p>

<p>The event is open to the public, please come and meet us. <a href="https://forms.office.com/Pages/DesignPageV2.aspx?subpage=design&amp;FormId=0ueuCdngDkei64yDImh2xxSFMNALCOVFg4-Z2Isvp6NUNlFYUkhKV0o1QVZGQVdGUFJIN0gxSEFLMi4u&amp;Token=81ef9158a7dc41d9bc45cd290157323c">#Don’t forget to register</a>.</p>

<p>As always, want to get in touch? <a href="https://discord.gg/z7QjZ538Vd">#Discord</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/radxchangeparis">#Twitter</a> or <a href="mailto:rxcfrance@gmail.com">#email</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Olivier Milla</name><email>olivier.milla@hey.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[On February 21-23, 2023, UNESCO will hold a 3-day conference on the topic of Internet for Trust in its Parisian headquarters. The event is co-organized by #RadicalXChange France, #leplusimportant and the #TESaCo programme.]]></summary></entry></feed>